CASS CASAREZ

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

Energetic, driven, and detail-oriented software developer on a mission to do good with their skills. Especially interested in web accessibility and other ways to make the internet available to as many people as possible regardless of zip code or lived experiences.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at 100devs | Saint Paul, MN

January 2022 - Present

- Collaborates with a team of developers throughout the world to create front-end and fullstack projects using best practices
- · Builds semantically structured full-stack web applications

Recent Projects:

Voting Tracker – In this accessible front-end web application, the user can select their age and type their location to get information about how to vote and where to learn more about their local elections.

Outfit Pick – This minimal accessible full-stack web application lets the user find an option of what to wear based on the weather outside.

Other Projects: Minimalist Pokedex, on-demand Twitch background color changer, cat feeding tracker, a resource about the LGBTQ+ community for people who speak Spanish, and many more online

Freelance Web Developer | Saint Paul, MN

January 2019 — Present

Creates static websites and web applications for clients across small and medium-sized businesses. Offers consultation on and talents in SEO, social media strategy and management, as well as writing for many types of media.

Clients include Opix Media, Inc. (Sarasota, Fla.) for "Suncoast People" show website and TIGERRS (Minneapolis) for website and social media upkeep.

Content Producer at Jamersan | Remote

January 2021 – January 2022

Researched and put together technical program instructions, video scripts, and blog posts for successful eCommerce company.

VOLUNTEERING

Out in Tech | Remote

June 2022

Helped rebuild a Wordpress-based website for a group in Africa as part of a single-day event with Out in Tech's Digital Corps. Main focus was creating user documentation.

CONTACT

casscodes.netlify.app

linkedin.com/in/cmcasarez

@cassdoescode

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

Javascript

Node.js

React

React Native

Expressjs

MongoDB

OOP

Web Accessibility

Web Design

Wordpress

GoDaddy

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin - Madison

2007 - 2011

B.A., Communication Arts